小黄人
200有周年纪念1976
华丽松糕鞋 大促销
罪犯唱片
Criminal records 也有犯罪前科的意思
极恶六天王
地下总部
耶嘿 家人们 坏蛋打击联盟可追不上姐
Whoo,baby! The anti-villain league can't catch this.
猜猜谁偷到了地图
Guess who stole the map?
贝莱.博顿
死壮大力士
哈利路亚
Hallelujah!
双节棍修女
拿来吧 你
I got this.
报仇者
尚格·夹顿
干得漂亮
Good work.
威酷魔王
传说中通向十二玉盘的藏宝图
The map forthe legendary Zodiac Stone,
我们会变成全世界最强大的坏蛋
we will become the most powerful villains in the world.
好了 准备出发
OK,let's get a move on.
我们今夜就启程去亚洲
We leave for Asia tonight.
好 让我看看....
Okay,let's see here....
我进去了
I'm in.
你好啊 小宝贝
Hello beautiful.
什么
What?
啊哈 十二玉盘 我的啦
Ahal Yes,the Zodiac Stone.
过不了多久 这股强大无比的力量就是我们的了
Soon,the power ofthis unstoppable beast will be ours.
噢 看在上帝的份上
Oh,for crying out loud!
快点 有一群难缠的机器人追着我
Hurry up! I got a bunch of deadly botsies on my tail.
收到收到
Roger that on the copy
开快点 姐妹
Step on it sister.
快点 赶紧的
Hurry up! Come on!
我拿到了 我拿到玉盘了
I got it. I got the stone.
谢谢你了 老家伙 极恶六天王现在有新首领了
Party's over old man. The vicious six has a new head honcho.
你被利用了 老傻子
Youjust got played,poor sucker!
等等 这个帮派是我成立的 我们是一个团队啊
Hold on. Istarted this group. We're ateaml
你们的忠诚呢
Where's your loyalty?
拉倒吧 我们可是坏蛋
Oh please,we're villains.
没有忠诚这一说
There's no such thing.
是时候给下一代让地方了
It's time forthe next generation.
小黄人 格 鲁 的 崛 起
今天对我说什么
你就要记得怎么做
要是发现欺骗我
看你怎样逃得过
砰砰
不要躲
只要你做
砰砰
假如有错
你怎能瞒过我
砰砰
周五舞动迪斯科
小学
安静下来
Quiet down,class.
小学 周五舞动迪斯科
安静 大家安静 同学们
Quiet down,class. People,people.
职业畅想日
你们长大后想做什么
So,what do you want to be when you grow up?
我想当一名医生
Iwanna be a doctor.
太棒了 布拉德利
Wonderful. Bradly.
我想成为一名教师
Iwantto be a teacher.
不 你不想
No,you do not.
-我 我 -你说
-Me,me. -Yes?
我想成为消防员 同时当总统 还要开赛车
Iwantto be afireman,who's also the president and also drive race cars.
真激动人心啊
Exciting.
那你呢 格鲁
And what about you Gru?
极恶六天王
格鲁
Gru
我啊 我想成为...
Me,Iwant to be....
一个超级大坏蛋
a supervillain
小垃圾
Loser.
-比利 -爸爸
-Billy. -Daddy!
-布拉德 -妈妈
-Brad. -Moml!
格鲁 亲妈妈一口
Grul Kiss ala mama.
哇哦 我最喜欢的小亲威
Woah. My favorite tiny relatives.
不 大家伙 别立
No. Guys,come on.
我在学校还得维持形象呢
Hey,I got an image to uphold here.
好吧 嘿 你们准备好看电影了吗
OK. Hey. Are you guys prep for the movie?
出发咯
Let's go
大白鲨
本场票已售罄
雏形机
游乐场
危险区
我可是弹球巫师
Oh! I am a pinball wizard.
咻 咻 咻 咻 咻 咻
Swish swish swish swish swish swish.
好
OK
芝士炸弹
芝士射线 芝士射线 芝土射线
Cheese ray! Cheese ray! Cheese rayl
别拿芝士射我 兄弟
Don' cheese me,bro.
小费罐
骑走脂肪
啊 奶油 好好吃
So creamy,so delicious,
满满的卡路里
账单 杂志
Bills magazine.
商场绿邮
S&H green stamps.
什么
Huh?
优先配送
绝密 致:格鲁先生
极恶六天王
额滴个老天爷啊
Holy guacamole.
在哪听 我们去哪听
Where can we listen? Where can we listen?!
你好 格鲁先生
Hello Mr. Gru.
我们收到了你加入世界一流坏蛋团队
Weve received your application to the world's best supervillain team,
极恶六天王的申请
The Vicious 6.
最近正好空出一个位置
Arecent opening has become available.
-然后 -然后呢
-And -And?
你的面试在明天中午
Your interview is tomorrow at noon.
-好激动呀 -好激动呀
-Dy-na-mite! -Dynamitel
请前往417大街
Please go to 417 Main Street.
密码是 "你一点都不好"
The password is "you're no good."
你一点都不好
"你一点都不好"
"Youre no good."
打起精神来 孩子 因为这盘邀请碟要炸了
Now,get up from the down,son,because this invitation is gonna explode,baby!
爆炸 哦不不不
Explode? Oh,no,no,no,no,nol
重大新闻 妈妈
Very big news,mom!
妈
Mom?
什么情况
What?
妈 这个浑身大汗的人是谁 他把房子都震臭了
Mom,who is this sweaty guy? He's stinking up the house.
我还以为你在煮卷心菜
Ithought you were cooking cabbage.
他是我的新格鲁
He's my new guru.
告诉你的小怪朋友们 它们最好发挥点用处
Tell your weird buddies. They better start pulling their weight around here.
要不然我就把他们赶出去
or I'm kicking them out.
他们把我幽静的气氛都捞和没了
They are killing my mellow vibes.
嘿 我可听见了
Hey! I heard that.
贝莱.博顿
双节棍修女
尚格夹顿,
死壮大力士
威酷魔王
报仇者
极恶六天王
走吧 去把好消息告诉大家伙
Come on,let's go tell the troop the good news.
先生们 向地下室进发
Gentlement,to the basement.
也就是我们的新邪恶大本营
AKA,our new evil lair.
太棒了 真不错看起来 伙计们
This is fantastic. Oh. Such a looks good,guys.
我第一个收恶巢穴 起鸡皮疙瘩了
My first evil lair. Goosebumps!
成功过程中难免得跌倒几次
Well you gotta break a few eggs to make an omelette.
我说的对吧
Am I right?
做得真棒 瑞安
Good job,Ryan.
我说 做得真棒
Is aid,"Good job."
算了
Never mind.
阿德里安 麦克 真棒
Adriannel Mackl Lookin' good.
乔 家里人怎么样
Joel How's the family?
所有人 到这里来
Okay. Everybody,get over here.
听着 系好背带裤 戴好眼镜
Now,listen up. Buckle your overalls. Hold on to your goggles.
极恶六天王明天想要见我
The Vicious 6 wants to meet me tomorrow.
小老板 小老板 小老板
Mini Boss! Mini Boss! Mini BosS!
好了好了 我不是小黄人
All right. All right. Im not mini.
不要这样叫我 另外 他们还没有接受我
Please stop calling me that,and also,they haven' accepted me yet.
你好 奥托 怎么了
Hello,Otto. What is it?
嗯 那那个对
Uh huh. Well,tha-tha-yes-
我会.. 好了 你知道什么最有意思吗
I would,... Okay,you know it would be fun?
我们来玩安静游戏
Let's play the quiet game.
不论如何 谢谢大家今天的六苦工作
Anyway,thanks for the hard work today everyone.
我要去休息了
I gotta go get some rest.
明天是我人生中的大日子
Tomorrow is the biggest day of my life.
世界人民注意了 格鲁来了
Watch out,world. Here comes Grul
小老板 小老板
Mini Boss! Mini Bossl!
都说了我不是 算了....
Im not... uhh...
极恶六天王
这些家伙是最坏的 我真的不敢相信
Oh,these guys are the best. I can't believe it.
极恶六天王
小老板
Mini Boss?
我明白 但是我需要好好睡一觉 出去
Yeah,Igetit,but I need a good night's sleep,so get out,
极恶六天王
行吧 看在你做了恒梦的份上 不过就今天一晚
Okay,fine,fine. Because you had a nightmare,but just tonight.
极恶六天王
虽然我不相信你做噩梦的鬼话
I'm not buying the nightmare story,thoug
真的 你也做噩梦了吗
Oh really,you too?
进来吧
Get in,
-晚安 -晚安
-Good night. -Good night.
好好好 晚安
Yes,yes,yes. Good night.
我只是想睡个党
I just want to get some sleep.
坏蛋频道
爆炸新闻 极亚六天王要重写坏蛋守则
Breaking news! The Vicious 6 is ready to rewrite the rules of villainy.
极恶六天王
世上的坏蛋们
Villains of the world,
三天后 当午夜的时钟敲响 正月初一到来之际
In three days when the clock strikes midnight and the Chinese New Year begins,
这个坏东西的力量将会被释放
this bad boys' power is gonna be unleashed.
有了十二生肖的力量
With the power of the Zodiac,
我们将会摧毁坏蛋打击联盟
we're gonna take out the anti villain league.
坏蛋打击联盟
极恶六天王
极恶六天王将成为星球上最强大的坏蛋
And The Vicious 6 will be the most powerful villains on the planet.
明白了吗
Can you dig it?
我明白吗 明白什么
DoIdig it? DoIdig it?
我不明白 没什么好明白的
I don't dig it. There's nothing to dig.
他们以为可以把我丢下等死吗
They thought they could leave me for dead,huh?
把我像块臭猪肉一样丢在路边
Kick me to the curb like a piece of old meat.
他们不知道这会有什么后果
Oh. They got no idea what's coming?
我要让他们遭受相同的待遇
Oh.I'm gonna make them suffer for what they have done to me
-等着吧 -纳克鲁斯先生
-Oh boy. -Hey,Mr. Knuckles.
干什么
What?!
我们 只是想问一下这周会发工资吧
We uhh.... just wanted to make sure we be getting paid this week.
知识就是金钱 我传授点知识给你们吧
What about value? Pm paying you with knowledge,.
你有吗
You are?
第一课 时刻准备着
Lesson one,always be prepared.
第二课
Lesson two,
比利时五臂捅鼻
The Belguim Five-arm Nose-Pinch.
第三课
And lesson 3,
立陶宛脱毛
The Lithuanian Haircut.
这些知识付钱都买不来
That's worth all the money in the world.
各位 别介意 我会付你们钱的
Hey guys,forget about it. You're going to get paid.
但首先 我们需要把我的玉盘拿回来
But first,we got to get my stone back.
我预见坏人格鲁的崛起
I see a bad Gru arising.
我预见一个大坏蛋走来
Isee avillain on his way.
我预见与坏蛋共处一室
I'm going now in the room with my heroes,
他们会因为我的坏坏爱惨我
They're gonna love me because Im the best.
极恶六天王
今晚要好好发挥
Don't mess up tonight.
极恶六天王
我即将加入极恶六天王
Youre going to join The Vicious 6.
坏蛋格鲁来了 我....
Here is the bad Gru and did II...
你们
Guys....
你们也想去吗
Oh,you want to come?
行 行 好吧
Right right.... Okay....
你们找到我 找我帮忙的时候 你们干了什么
When you guys tracked me down and responded to my help,what did then?
我脑子里全是 这些小黄土豆是什么啊
I was like "who are these tiny tater tots?"
寻求帮助
从哪里搞来这么多牛仔背带裤的
"And where did they get so much denim?"
但你们就是不肯放弃
And youre just wouldn't quit.
收养我们
我们爱格鲁
好吧 我投降 快进来吧
All right,Isurrender. Come on in.
收养我们  小老板格鲁
从那之后我们一起度过了很多快乐时光
Weve had some great times since then,
但情况是 极恶六天王 他们是大组织
But the thing is... The Vicious 6,they're the big leagues.
你们都 很棒
And you guys... are.... great....
你们在坏蛋基地做的工作
and so the job you did in the lair.
超级无敌棒
A plus.
但我想的是
It's just what I was thinking
世上还有很多其他坏蛋
is that there are a lot of other villains in the world.
明白吗
You know?
算了 听着
Never mind. Look.
我想这回我得自己单干了
I think I just need to fly solo on this.
回头见 小可爱们
See you later,alligators.
瞎啊 差点撞到我
Hey,I'm walking here.
罪犯唱片
走起
Here we go.
请问一下 先生
EXcuse me. Sir?
我只想问问 你是 "一点都不好"吗
I was just wondering you're no good.
你特别好 是我不好
You're good. My mistake.
对不起 我不是故意吓到你的
Sorry I didn't mean to scare you.
我是在...试验我的新发明
Im just...trying out this new invention of mine.
我叫它"答黏手指"或者"聪明黏黏"
Icall it "sticky fingers" or "smart g800."
我还没决定好叫哪个名字
I haven't quite landed on the name yet.
过来
Come here.
我无意中听到你在找什么
I overheard you were looking for something....
特别的东西
Special.
是啊 我在找"你一点都不好"
I yes,Iwas hoping you're no good.
去第三间欣赏这首歌吧
Ithink youll enjoy listening in Booth 3.
琳达.朗丝黛
你一点都不好
这边走
Right this way.
暂停使用
就是这 别声张 小点声
This is it. Mums the word. Keep it down.
祝你好运 孩子 好好表现
Good luck. Let her have it,Son.
谢谢你
Thanks mister
尼法里奥先生
Nefario
是尼法里奥博士
That's Doctor Nefario.
给 拿上这个
Here,take this.
以后要是出名了 别忘了是我给你的第一把装备噢
If you ever get famous,remember who gave you your first gadget,
好
Okay.
要是他告诉我了我不会怪他
I wouldn't blame him if he said to me
你一点都不好
You're no good
反方向旋转试试
Try backwards.
欢迎拜访极恶六天王
Welcome to The Vicious 6.
这也太厉...
That's pretty...
你们好
Hello.
各位都是来面试的吗
Everybody here for the interview?
我也是
Me too.
你们待会儿想搞些什么
So what do you guys got going on later?
是要干点坏事
Are you up to no good?
还是要搞点恶作剧
Are you gonna get into some mischief?
好吧
okay
让第一个进来
Send the first one in.
格鲁先生 你可以进去了
They're ready to see you Mr. Gru.
噢 太好了
Oh,good good.
极恶六天王
尊敬的坏蛋们
Distinguished villains,
我叫格鲁
My name is Gru,
我觉得我说话的声音太大了 我们之间的距离
I feel like I'm talking too loud,even though our proximity
好像不需要那么大声
doesn't require this kind of volume.
如果有人在我10岁的时候告诉我
If you told me when I was ten,
我有机会去接班我最喜欢的坏蛋
if I would have the chance to fill the shoes of my favorite villain ever,,
威酷魔王的位置
Wild Knuckles
我一定会说 "你脑子进泥石流了吧"
I would say "you got rocks in your head,"
但我现在11多零9个月了 我有信心了
but nowthat I'm 11 and 3/4,it makes a lot more sense.
谁把这孩子选进来的
All right,who let the kid in?
我以为他只是个子矮
Ithought he was this tiny man.
你没事吧
What's wrong with you?
你真觉得一个小不点孩子能当坏蛋吗
You seriously think a puny little child can be a villain .
呃 当然了 我很卑鄙的
Umm... Yes. I'm pretty despicable.
惹恼我的后果可严重了
You don't want to cross me.
能偷走上古玉盘
Evil is for adults,
能大肆破坏的成年人才配得上"邪恶"二字
who steal powerful ancient stones and wreak havoc,
你这种应该在学校学习的小鬼头还是省省吧
and not fortubby little pups who should be at school learning
哪凉快哪待着去
taking a recess.
该死的 我停不下来
Suck,I can' stop.
等你有了能打动我的事迹再来吧
Come back when youve done something to impress me
下一个
Who's next?
我是翼人 极恶六天王的下一位成员
I am Wingman,the next member of The Vicious 6.
看看 这飞行之力
Behold,the power of fight,Sir.
好吧 别闹了 我出手了
All right,joke's over. Show time.
这人也太能飞了
Woothis is a big balloon.
对对 转向 就是这样
Yeah,yeah,turn around that”s right.
家人们 拉过来 把他拉过来
Bring him in. Bring him in,boysl
他拿走了玉盘
He took the stone.
抓住他
Caught him!
封锁大楼
Lock down the building.
我..别看我 没什么好看的
I did. nothing to see here.
噢 看看 弗兰普顿重生 品味不镜
Oh,look at you. Frampton Comes Alive! Nice choice.
我....
I uh...
继续走你的
Just keep walking.
看看 一个孩子吗
Look at that. A kid?
伙计们
Guys.
你们在这干什么
What are you doing here?
别说了 快上车
Okay.Just get on.
-他往哪走了 -小小偷在那
-Which way did he go? -There is that little thief
开门 送快递的
Knock knock. Delivery!
那个恶魔般的孩子在那
The demon child!
奥托 把玉盘带回基地
Otto,take the stone back to the lair.
我来转移他们的注意力
I'll distract them.
别吧 这时候故障拜托给点力啊
No,not now. Come on,come on.
好吧 宝贝
Yeah,baby.
我来处理
I'll handle this.
希望你能享受你的短暂余生
Hope you enjoy the rest of your short life.
拜托别故障了 快点 快点
Please work. Come on,come on,come on
等着我们找你算账吧 小屁孩
We're coming for you,tiny manl
他们都说一个孩子不可能成为真正的坏蛋
They all said a kid wouldn't be a real villain.
但是 这个孩子刚刚从坏蛋头子那偷走些东西
We-he-ell... This kid just stole something from the worst villains in the world.
等我把这个还给他们的时候 他们会说
When I bring it back to them,they're going to say....
"我们犯了个大错误"
"We have made aterrible mistake."
"请加入我们吧"
"Please join Us."
"加入我们吧 格鲁" 我会说
"Please Gru" and I will say....
好吧 我会成为极恶六天王的新成员
Yes! I will be the newest member of The Vicious 6.
现在我需要奥托
Now all I need is Otto.
奥托在哪
Where is Otto?
不行 什么"奥托等会就来" 他现在就得在这儿
No,not "Otto le komay" He needs to come in now.
-奥托 -小老板
-Ottol -Mini boss!
你来了
There you are....
你带回来了吗
You got it?
这是.... 你是在拖我后腿吗
Is this.... Are you pulling on my legs right now?
奥托 玉盘去哪里了
Otto,where's the Stone?
生日快乐
宠物石
你是把我的未来换给别人了吗
Did you just trade my future?
就为了个宠物石头
For a pet rock?!
行吧 我自己去
Okay I'll go..
你说的生日派对在哪里
Where was this birthday party?
无语 无语死了
This is unacceptable. Unacceptablel
我和你们说过 你们还不能加入大组织
I told you guys that you weren' ready forthe big leagues
你还用行动证明了我是对的
and you have proven me correct.
你们只会捣乱
All you do is mess everything up.
啊 搞什么
Ugh! What?!
我妈说的对
My mom was right,
你们不属于这里 你们被解雇了
You do not belong here. You're fired.
我自己去找那玉盘
I'm going to find that stone.
我回家的时候 希望你们都消失了
When I get home,you all better be gone.
还有 奥托 你那嘴别再叭叭了
And Otto,close your yapper!
BGM：Goodbye to Love by Carpenters
与爱道别
I'll say goodbye to love
没有人在乎我的生死
No one ever cared if l should leave or die
一次又一次 爱的机会与我肩而过
Time and time again the chance for love has passed me by
凯文 别跟着我了 我没你们更好
Kevin,no,I will be better off on my own.
我所知道的关于爱的一切就是没有爱如何生活
And all I konw of love is how to live without it
我就是找不到爱
I just can't seem to find it
所以我下定决心 我必须独自生活
So l've made my mind up I must live my life alone
虽然这并不容易我想我一直都知道
And though it's not the easy way I guess I've always know
与爱道别
I'd say goodbye to love
我的真心没有未来
There are no tomorrows for this heart of mine
时间肯定会抹去这些苦涩的回忆
Surely time will lose these bitter memories
我会发现原来还有一个人可以相信
And I'll find that there is someone to believe in
为了我人生的值得而活
And to live for something I could live for
小老板
Mini boss!
对不起 我还以为这样就能打动你们
I'm sorry.I thought you'll be impressed
我能和贝莱·博顿聊聊吗
Can I just speak to Belle Bottom
威酷魔王
Wild Knuckle!
你居然还活着
You're alive?
哇 我最喜欢的坏蛋居然绑架了我误
Wow,my favorite villain is also my kidnapper.
要是不杀我 这事儿我能吹一辈子
This could be a great opportunity if you don't kill me.
闭嘴 把玉盘给我
Shut up and give me the stone.
啊对对对 玉盘
Ahh. Yes. The stone.
是这样的
Here's the thing about that.
这个故事说起来还挺有趣
It's kind of a funny story.
快把玉盘给他
Give it to him.
事态马上就要严重起来了
It's all going to go South very quickly.
这他妈是什么
What the heck is this?
玉盘到底在哪 小屁孩
Where is it,boy?
我没有 不在我这儿
I don't have it,I don't have it.
我知道你把它藏起来了
I know you're hiding it somewhere.
我没有 我保证 我用我的生命起誓
I'm not,I'm not. I swear. Cross my heart and hope to die.
死我也不会干这事儿
Stick a needle in my eye.
别把我扔下去
Don't actually do that though.
来人 把电话拿来
Somebody bring me a phone.
打电话给家里人吧 勒索时间到了
Call home. It's ransom time.
别别别 我妈可能还会给你钱感谢你把我绑走
No,no,no. My mom will probably pay you to keep me.
别想耍我 快打
Good one. Call
你谁啊
Who is this?
凯文什么
Kevin lay what?
你逗我呢 小屁孩还有手下
You kidding me? You got henchmen?
完了 我死定了
Well,that's the end of that.
你给我听好 把玉盘带来旧金山
Listen,you. Bring the stone to me in San Francisco.
格林街6830号 听见没 给你两天时间
6830 Green Street,got it? Now you got two days
不然就别想再见到你的小老板了
oryou are never gonna see your little boss again.
啊哈哈 那玉盘子
Oh ho ho... The stone.
给我叔叔啦 这东西比较适合他嘛
Gave that to my uncle. It's more his style.
我都说了 我不知道他去哪了 笨蛋
I told you,I don't know where he went you stupid Twinkies,
烦死了
Not cool man.
去往旧金山之旅
旧金山
San Francisco.
出发吧 是时候把我们的玉盘拿回来了
Let's rock and roll. Time to get our stone back.
格鲁先生 我们来咯
Were coming for you Mr. Gru,
哈利路亚
Hallelujah!
国际机场
去旧金山 好的 您要怎么支付呢
San Francisco. Okay. How will you be paying?
哈哈 你要再是支付个毛球我们就可以把你升去头等舱呢
Oh great. You know,if you have any hairballs,we can upgrade you to 1st class.
快滚
Get out.
我不得不在拉瓜迪亚调头
And I had to turn back at LaGuardi
a.
嗨 多丽
Hey Dolly.
要花生吗
Peanut?
好的 谢谢
Oh. Yes,please.
一颗花生
Peanut.
花生花生
Peanut!
要花生吗
Peanut?
花生要吗
要花生吗
Peanut?
嘿 宝宝 花生要吗
Hey baby,Peanut?
看见我啦看不见啦
You see me? You see me not.
旧金山
你小子有点东西 敢从极恶六天王手里偷东西
You got real moxie kid,stealing from The Vicious 6.
有点东西 真的吗 这是威酷魔王对我的夸赞吗
I got moxie,really? Did I just receive a compliment from Wild Knuckles?
梦想成真啦
All my dreams are coming true right now.
那梦想要变成噩梦咯
Well it's about to become your nightmare.
欢迎使用我最新的酷刑装置迪斯科地狱
Welcome to my newest torture device. Disco inferno
你的小黄人最好在明天太阳下山之前赶过来哦
Your minions better get it by sundown tomorrow
如果48小时的迪斯科折磨不死你 那你就要被锯死啦
because if48 hours of disco won't kill you,the blade will.
啊啊啊 不要啊
Oooh! No,no,no,no,no,
前方死亡谷 最好现在回头路
三百里后有加油站
继续走继续走
Go go go.
格林街
下一站 格林街
Next up,Green Street.
威
酷
等等
Wait a minute.
有入侵者
Trespassers!
给我回来
Come back here.
别想跑 给我回来
Get your little butts back here.
周氏针灸
现在你会感觉有点痛
OK,now. You might feel a little pinch,
抓到你们了
Got you now.
好戏开始
Time to bring some fun.
周末有没有安排呀
Any plans for the weekend?
做五个深呼吸
Take five deep breaths.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
你们喜欢其负小孩子是吧
You like picking on little guys,huh?
睡你的午觉去吧 老东西
Go take a nap,old lady.
你敢叫我老东西
old lady?
我可是少林功夫大师
I am a master of the ancient Shaolin Art of Kung Fu.
回家找妈妈去吧
Get lost.
你们要是再敢问进我们的地盘 必死无疑
If you come backto our place,you're dead.
嘘 要是真的想感谢我 就赶紧走 我工作呢
Shh shh shh... You can thank me by going away. I'm working.
你们 想学功夫
You? Want to learn Kung Fu?
我已经不再收弟子了
My teaching days are over.
我只想过平静的生活
This is my life now,
好吧
Fine.
你们是我徒弟了
I will teach you.
嘿
Hey,
这些不是给你吃的
those are not for you.
你要做的是给我卖 东西
The name of the game is sell,sell,sell.
特百惠派对
什么情况
What?!
格鲁在哪里
Where is Gru?
我怎么知道 你们这些花里胡哨的装扮是什么情况
How should I know? What's with the costumes?
离万圣节还有好几个月呢 你们穿得傻不拉几和干什么
Halloween was four months ago. You look stupid,
滚开
Buzz off. Shoo.
我的松肉粉快好了
I'm getting my meat tenderizer.
亲爱的 让我来帮你吧
Let me help you with that,dearie.
快告诉我 那小孩在哪儿
Now,where's the boy?
我不是有意要恐吓你们的
I didn't mean to scare you.
别担心 我们没有生他的气
Don't worry,we're not mad at him.
我们只是想....
We just want to....
招募他
hire him.
那东西在哪里
Where is it?
威酷魔王 他还活著
Wild Knuckles? He's alive
那孩子跟他组队了
And working with the kid?
下一站旧金山
We're going to San Francisco.
走吧
Let's hit it.
你们最好赔偿我的房顶
You had better be paying for my roof .
眼前一亮 对吧
Pretty groovy,huh?
基本功
我们从基本腿法练起
We begin with a basic kick.
你们试试看
Now,you.
好吧 不练这个了
Okay.... No kicking.
这个叫瓜锤 是一件兵器
This is a melon hammer. It's a weapon.
这位是弗莱德 他是个人形靶
This is Fred. Heis a dummy.
永远不要低估一个人形靶
Never underestimate a dummy,
出手 攻击
Now,attack.
不要跟我说你们碎不了木板
Don't tell to me "I can not break this wood."
自我怀疑只是心理作用
But doubt exists only in the mind.
你们知道我会对自己说什么吗
You know what I say to my mind.
轮到你们了
Now,you.
凯文啊 凯文 唉
Kevin,Kevin,Kevin.
好吧 看来你们还没做好学哲学的准备
Okay. Clearly,we are not ready for philosophy.
那我们就光训练吧
Let's just train.
好好休息 明天的课会更累
Rest up. Tomorrow's going to be even worse.
什么 你们要辞职
What? You're quitting?
我都说了 等拿到了玉盘
Itold you when I get that stone,
我们就能所向披靡
We're going to be unstoppable.
我已经受够了
I have had enough.
没什么比一个上了年纪的坏蛋更可悲的了
There's nothing sadderthan an aging villain.
再见了 臭老头
So long,old man,
别这样各位 我们可是一个团队
Guys,come on. We're a team.
希望你会喜欢
Hope you like it.
这里是天堂吗
Is this heaven?
我刚刚开除了那群狗腿子 知道为什么吗
I just had to fire my henchman. You know why?
因为他们失职了
Because they weren't getting the job done.
好了 我现在要给你松绑 因为我
OK I'm just gonna untie you now because I
我 我需要你为我做一些家务
I I I need you to do some stuff for me around the house.
可能你 你懂的 有个伴总好过孤身一人
You might be,you know,kind of nice to have a little company around here.
是啊 没错
Oh,yeah.
坏蛋做家务
Villains just doing some chores.
天知道我们会遇到什么糟心事呢
Who knows what kind of trouble we could get into.
那是什么
What's that?
-你的邪恶坏笑吗 -显而易见
-That's your evil chuckle? -Obviously.
简直糟透了
Well,it stinks.
听起来就像个误食了卡祖笛的小丑
You sound like a clown who swallowed a kazo
o.
真的吗 那你就像一个土埋半截的老巫师
Really? Well,you look like a wizard going through an end of life crisis,
唐·里克斯:著名讽刺喜剧演员
别太嚣张了 唐.里克斯
Easy now,Don Rickles.
唐·里克斯是谁
Who's Don Rickles?
响尾蛇出没
小家伙
Dude.
我差点以为你要不行了
I thought we lost youthere for a minute.
嘿 别激动 别激动
Hey,chill chill,
你想要这个是吗 小兄弟
You wanna try this one,little dude?
好兄弟 你是要去哪里
Hey soul brother where jetting off to?
旧金山啊
Frisco Disco!
你可真是个幸运的小家伙 我正好要去沿海那一带
It's so lucky day chickTm heading up the coast.
我可以载你一程
I could drop you off on the way.
世界上最大的香蕉
旧金山 75公里
从泳池开始 要打扫得干干净稳
Start with the pool. This place gotta be spick and span.,
那你要干什么
What are you doing?
你看上去就像我妈妈在感恩节烤过头的火鸡
You look like the overcooked turkey my mom makes on Thanksgiving.
哦对了 我忘了提
Oh yeah,I forgot to mention,,
这里面都是我的宠物鳄鱼
the pool is filled with my pet crocodiles.
好啊好啊 这吓不倒我
Yeah,well well... doesn't scare me.
小心点 可别缺了条胳膊
Be careful.I can't have you lose an arm
待会我还想让你换灯泡呢 给我
because they need you to change some light bulbs after this,yeah.
我来给你演示一下
Let me show you how it's done.
别咬
Knock it off.
嘿 哦 不妙
Hey. Whoa! Oh,no.
马文 别这样 快停下
Marvin,no,no. Stop that.
把网递给我
The net.
我来救你
I got you.
我抓住了 加把劲
I got you.I got you,
我没救到
I don't got you.
抓住我的手
Take my hand.
抓住你了
Got you.
你本可以跑的 但你....但你却留下来救了我
You could have ran. But you.... But you didn't.
我说过的 你是我在这个世界上最喜欢的坏蛋
I told you,you were my favorite villain in the world.
我可不能让你被鳄鱼吃掉
I could not let you get eaten by crocodiles.
即使那场面可能看起来会很酷
Even though that would have been kinda cool to watch.
所以.....你是想成为一个很历害的大坏蛋 对吗
So Soyouwantto be a great villain,huh?
那是我一直所追求的
That's all I ever wanted.
你想.... 我也不知道怎么说 你是想我....
You wantto,I don't know,you want me....
你是想让我教你点什么吗
You want meto teach you athing or two?
有很多斗士问过我 "我是如何成为一名武林高手的"
Many fighters have asked me,"how did I become a great master?"
唤醒内心的野兽
即使是小人物也能成大事
Even the smallest of us are capable of great things.
你只需要深入你的内心 寻找藏匿在此的野兽 然后....
You just dig down deep,find your inner beast,and....
现在到你们了
Now,you try.
唤醒你内心的野兽
Find your inner beast.
来阻止这个腾空 飞踢
Stop this kick.
我们要练的还有很多
We have a lot more work to do
BGM: Born To Be Alive by 王嘉尔
我们天生就
就是活着
天生就是活
对 咱们生 生 生
活着
To be alive
有人问我 为什么从来不找地方 停下安家 家 家
但我一直都不要那些 别人需要的玩意儿 没意义 义 义
没错 我们天生
Yes,we were born,born,born
世上活着真好
活着真好 活着真好
凯文 斯图尔特 鲍勃 你们出师了
Kevin,Stuart,and Bob,you are ready.
不不不 不是的 别跑
No,no,no,no,no.
我是说给你们发功夫少年勋章
Ready for your Kung Fu junior achievement badges.
他们完了
They're dead.
国民银行
抢劫的第一准则 永远沉漫在你的人设里
First rule of heist,always stay in character.
好的 爷爷
Got it grandpa.
抱歉 关门了
史上最好的爷爷
嘿 不介意我们用下洗手间吧....
Say,you mind if we use the john....
我孙子德克斯特撑不到回家了
My boy Dexter here can't hold it in till we get home.
邪恶银行
The Bank of Evil.
要开始了 孩子
It's showtime,kid.
听我指令 记好你的暗号
Follow my lead and don't forget your cue.
你好 我…我想兑现这个支票
Hello I...I just need to cash this.
哇哦 好大的银行呀
Oh wowie zowie! What a big bank!
这有多少保安呀
How many security guards are in here?
这小东西是谁
Who's this little guy?
这是我孙子 他还没学会小孩子应该多看少说
Well that's my grandson who still has not learned that children should be seen and not heard,
哈哈 小孩子 其实我也有个儿子
Haha,kids. I actually have a son of my own.
唷 他看起来好像个怪胎
Yeah,you look so weird.
哦哈哈 别听他瞎说
Oh haha,don't listen to him
你儿子看起来很 呢...
our son Is Very Un....
可爱
cute.
救命 我看到天堂之光了 海伦 我来了
Help I'm seeing a white light. Helen,I'm coming for you.
海伦 我来陪你了....
Helen,I'm coming for you....
救命呀
Oh... help!
救救我爷爷
Help my grandpa.
快来个人救救他
Somebody help him.
快救救我爷爷
My grandpa!
要命了不行了
This is the big one.
你听到了吗
You hear that?
是甜美的天使之声
It's the sweet sound of angels.
救救我 我眼前开始走马灯了
Do something,my life is flashing before my eyes.
错了错了另一边另一边
No,no,no. The other way,the other wa
y.
我们来了 大家往后退
All right. Everyone stand back.
完了 …
Uh-oh...
-离手 -等一下 等
-Clear. -Wait a minute,wait.
坚持住 老兄
Don't give up on me now,buddy.
没事了没事了 我感觉好多了
No,no,no.I'm feeling better.
离手
Clear!
最大电流
Maximum charge.
离手
Clear.
你们救了我爷爷
You saved my grandpa.
我们...我们是来抢劫的吗
Did we... Did we do the heist?
我爷爷在说胡话了
Grandpa say the darnest things.
你掉了这个
You dropped this.
看我拿了什么
Look what I got.
嘿 不错
Hey,not bad.
干得还不错
Not bad at all.
我们合作得很棒
We make a good team.
真的吗
We do?
是啊 嘿 我们得这样做下去
Oh yeah,hey we got to keep at it.
看好接下来我要教你的东西
Wait till you see what I'm gonna teach you next.
我等不及了
I cannot wait.
会很有趣的喔
Oh,this is gonna be fun.
出击时间到
Time to strike.
他们不在这
They're not here.
分头去找
Fan out and find them.
旧金山出大事了
Something big is going down in Frisco.
喔呼 到了
Whoo. There it is.
这可真是段激动人心的旅程啊 小家伙
It's been one heck of a ride,little man.
我会想你的
You know,I'm gonna miss you.
嘿 太客气了 祝你好运
Hey,so welcome. Good luck.
小朋友 你在老做派那学不到什么
My friend,you're not gonna learn from the old school.
啊这
Umm?
天呐....
Oh no...
坏蛋日报
疯狂纳克鲁斯成立极恶六天王
我不敢相信他们竟然这样对我
I can't believe they did this to me.
我…我把我会的都教给了他们
I…I taught them everything they know.
我们可是团队啊
We were a team.
唉
Umm?
算了
I give up.
嘿
Hey.
作为坏蛋 你真的很厉害
You are a great bad guy.
他们都是愚蠢的傻蛋
They are stupid idiots.
我唯一梦想就是和我的朋友们一起做坏事
Only dream I ever had was doing bad stuff with my buddies.
而现在的我 又老....又孤独...
Now look at me,old.... alone....
好吧 你的确老了
Well,you are old.
但你并不孤独
But you're not alone.
好吧 听好了 老伙计
All right,listen up,buster.
我俩新建一个组合 名字就叫做
We are starting a newteam and it's going to be called
坏蛋传奇
The Terrible Twos.
我们之后再想个拉风的名字
We can find a better name later,
不过现在我们得找到那块玉盘
but right now we are going to find that stone
让大家知道你宝刀未老
and show everybody that you still got it.
拜托 你就是个小屁孩 别做梦了
Come on,youre just a little kid. It's over.
-回家去吧 -但你说过我们...
-Go home. -But you said we....
快回家去
Go home!
奥托
Otto?
Otto!
奥托 是我 小老板
Otto! Mini boss!
小老板
Mini boss!
奥托
Otto!
你找到玉盘了
You found the stone.
奥托 我真为你骄傲
Otto,I'm so proud of you.
快点 没时间了
Hurry we don't have much time.
我们得把它交给威酷魔王
We got to get this to Wild Knuckles
好久不见 小废物
Long time no see,punk.
拿来吧你
I'll take that.
好诶
Yes!
别动
Don't move!
坏蛋打击联盟到场 你们被逮捕了
Anti-Villain League. You are under arrest.
好吧好吧 难道大家忘了现在几点了吗
Well well well everybody... Did you forget what time itis?
新年快乐
Happy New Year!
开火
Fire!
守住了
Stand your ground.
不 不 不 不 别想逃
No,no,no,no,no,no,no,no,no,NO!
你想跑哪去
Where do you think youre going?
偷了我们的东西 是时候付出代价了
You stole from us,and now you're gonna pay.
等着被撕碎吧
Enjoy being torn apart.
伙计们
Guys!
噢...我们何不来一场公平的决斗呢
oh.... Why don't we make this a fair fight?
噢…你们以为我说真的吗
Oh... You thought I was serious?
嘿 叛徒们
Hello,traitors!
还记得我吗
Remember me?
你
You?
你毁了我所拥有的一切
You can leave me for dead,
我可以和你同归于尽 但我绝不允许你伤害那小孩
You destroy everything I own,but I will not let you hurt that kid.
噢...所以你要救这个小孩
Oh.. So you're gonna save the kid?
就凭你 还有帮手吗
Yeah,you and what army?
很好....他们就是我的帮手
Okay....this army.
挖掘内心深处 唤醒内心的野兽吧
Dig down deep. Find your inner beast.
奥托
Otto.
快点 再快点
Hurry! Faster!
没事了
Gottcha!
离他远点
Get away from him.
干掉那小孩
Destroy the kid.
不
No!
被小屁孩打败是什么感受啊
How does it feel to be beaten by the tiny little bug?
你们真是棒极了
You guys were amazing.
你们这功夫 是从哪学的
The Kung Fu where did that come from?
很显然 你们被重新雇用了
Obviously you guys are re-hired.
都交给你了
It's all yours.
噢 不 威酷魔王
Oh,no. Wild Knuckles.
-格鲁 -嘿
-Gru -Hey
你会没事的 对吗
You're gonna be OK,right?
不用担心我 孩子
Don't worry about me,kid.
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
终于抓住你了
Finally.
你会在牢里待很久 很久
You are going awayfor along,long time.
是吗 我可不这么想
Yeah,well I wouldn't bet on it.
不
No.
之后见 小子
See you soon kiddo.
BGM: You Can' t Always get What You Want(小黄人版)
今天我在一个接待会上见到了她
她手中端着一杯酒
我知道她会遇到她的命中注定
威酷魔王是我最喜欢的坏蛋
Wild Knuckles was my favorite villain.
可以让她无拘无束的人
虽然我们相处时间不长 但我们在一起的美好时光
We didn't have much time together but the time we did have....
不你不可能总能得到你想要的
我都感激不尽
I'm so grateful for
而现在 身边少了你的陪伴 你也无法见证我的成长
I've been thinking about how you won't see me grow up or be there
你不可能总能得到你想要的
也无法看见我要去做的坏事
for all the terrible things that rm going to do
但请相信 这些坏事一定会坏透的
Believe me,they're gonna some awful things
如果你想试图寻找的话
你会得到你所需要的
我会让你以我为傲的
But I'm going to make you proud.
因为你 我要成为最厉害的坏蛋
I'm going to be the best villain ever because of you.
是你教会了我一个道理
Because youtaught me what matters,
一个人是做不了坏事的
you can't do anything alone.
找到属于自己的大家庭
ind your tribe.
永远在一起 永远不分开
And never ever let them go.
奥托
Otto.
今天我在一个接待会上见到了她
她手中端着一杯酒
我知道她会遇到她的命中注定
可以让她无拘无束的人
不 你不可能总能得到你想要的
你不可能总能得到你想要的
如果你想试图寻找的话
你会得到你所需要的
你最好别惹麻烦 小子
You better stay out of trouble,kid.
我会安分守己 好好生活
I will live a good and honest life.
你还活着
You're alive?
你真是让我大开眼界
You just blew my mind.
你是怎么做到的
How could you do that?
我等不及想像你一样 伪造死亡躲避警方了
I cannot wait to fake my own death to avoid the authorities.
把它定成你的目标你可以的孩子
Shoot for the moon,kid. Shoot for the moon.
回见 傻瓜们
See you later,Suckers.
你不可能总能得到你想要的
You Can' t Always get What You Want
但如果你尽力寻找的话 你会发现
But if you try sometims well you just might find
你会发现
You just might find
你会得到你所需要的
You get what you need
对不起 打烊了
Sorry,we're closed.
琳达·朗丝黛
你一点都不好
我是来谢谢你给我的这个装备
I just want to thank you for this.
在我手里很好用
Work like a child.
我就直说了
Alright,let me cut this easy.
我需要一个极具天赋的坏蛋科学家
I need a genius bad scientist.
你愿意为我效力吗
You want to come work for me?
不了 我受够给坏蛋做事的生活了
No,I am done with villainy off the happier horizon.
别想了 小朋友
Goodbye,you little chap.
噢… 好吧 别眨巴你们的大有眼睛了
Ohhh... All right,all right,Fine. Stop with a face.
我加入
I'm in.
想看点酷炫的东西吗
Wanna see something cool?
罪犯唱片
我不是在做梦吧
Are you kidding me?
大坏蛋 大坏蛋 大坏蛋
Big boss! Big boss! Big boss! Big boss!
大坏蛋 我喜欢
Big boss,I like that.